Guide to the Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society, Stanford University Chapter, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society, Stanford University Chapter, records
1902-1986
SC0758
Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society. Stanford University Chapter
1 Linear feet
Minutes and financial records, 1902-1968; member lists, 1902-1965; Frederick W. Crawford's history of the Stanford Chapter, 1976; program from the Stanford celebration of the Sigma Xi Centennial, 6 June 1986; and assorted Sigma Xi manuals and publications.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Minutes and financial records, 1902-1968; member lists, 1902-1965; Frederick W. Crawford's history of the Stanford Chapter, 1976; program from the Stanford celebration of the Sigma Xi Centennial, 6 June 1986; and assorted Sigma Xi manuals and publications.
Access Terms
Field, Isolde; Osserman, Robert; Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society. Stanford University Chapter; Stanford University. Department of Mathematics.; Universities and colleges--Research.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Meeting Minutes, 1902-1932, with loose items such as programs, by-laws, and one page of notes on alumni (Box 1)
  - Budget and Financial information, 1930-1952 (Box 1)
  - Member Lists, Meeting Minutes, Budget and Financial, 1932-65 and 1967-68 (Box 1)
  - Charter Members List, 1902, and subsequent members through 1933 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and Signatures of New Members, 1934-46 (Box 1)
  - Members of the Stanford Chapter, The Society of the Sigma XI, 1948 -1966 (Box 2)
  - Sigma XI: A History of the Stanford Chapter 1901 – 1976, Frederick W. Crawford (2 copies) (Box 2)
  - Sigma XI Centennial Celebration, The Scientific Research Society of North America, Stanford Chapter, program, 6 June 1986 (Box 2)
  - Manual of Procedure 1985, For Chapter and Club Officers of Sigma XI, The Scientific Research Society (Box 2)
  - Sigma XI: Half Century Record and History 1886 – 1936 (Box 2)